# MIR ASADUL HAQUE

Madhusasan, Gadijanga Kendrapara, OD 754134 Phone: +918018626848 E-mail: imasad@yahoo.com Website: http://aliasad.xyz/

## SUMMARY

1+ Year of Experience in Designing and developing Web applications. Expertise in Web development with .Net core, C#, Asp.Net, MVC, JavaScript, Bootstrap jQuery, CSS, HTML. Good knowledge in RDBMS (SQL server) which includes design and management of data.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## 01/2020–Present

## .NET MVC Developer, JDB Software Pvt Ltd., Bhubaneswar, OD

- Design, Development, and implementation of the Web applications, graphic, layout using C#.net MVC.
- Coding and Development using MVC Architecture
- Written STORED PROCEDURE in SQL SERVER.
- Providing Ideas and implementing them for performance tuning of the application.

## 06/2019-12/2019 .NET Developer, Ellmech Technology pvt ltd, Kolkata, WB

- Developed Web applications using C#.net4.0 and MSSQL Server 2008
- Development and maintenance of Programs module.
- Consulted with clients during the Development process.
- Written and designed database.

## SKILLS

Frontend	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootsrap4
Backend	Asp.net MVC, C#(4.0, 6.0)
Database	MSSQL,MySql
IDE	Visual Studio (2010, 2015, 2017), VSCode
Version Control	Github, Bitbucket

## **PROJECTS**

03-2020

Ekamra College – The purpose of Ekamra College Website is to automate the existing manual system by the help of fullfledged software, fulfilling the requirements, so that the Students can view study materials, Exam routine and important news related to their college, class, course in one place with a click of mouse.

- Have developed web application using code behind C# language in Microsoft Visual 2017 with MVC.
- Providing a better UI with the bootstrap 4, and CSS.
- Created Email notification service endpoint and also, involved in designing the email HTML templates.

 Proposed and implemented students notifications System for Students as well as Faculties.

01-2020 <u>BirenMitra Womens College</u> –The purpose of this project is to build connectivity between students and faculties to reduce the manual work for conveying any information regarding to the college. It tracks all the details about the Posts, Shares and Photos etc.

- Used C# as backend and MSSQL For Database
- Implemented client side validations using JavaScript, jQuery.
- Worked on creating responsive website for smart devices using responsive design (**RWD**) and media queries based on CSS, HTML5, and **Bootstrap** Front-End Framework.

O6-2019 Private Security Agency- The purpose of application is to automate the existing manual system by the help of fullfledged software, fulfilling the requirements, so that the user can apply for Licence, View ,Track Licence Status, get notifications and important news related to their License

- Used C#, VisualStudio2010, .NETframework4.0, SQL2008r2 to develope website.
- Written Stored Procedures.
- MVP Pattern followed for Asp.Net MVP Application.
- Created and WCF Service Libraries to exchange data between Desktop and Central Application and implement business logic.

## **EDUCATION**

2017-2019 **Master of computer Applications (MCA)**, Fakir Mohan University, Balasore, OD

2014–2017 **Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA)**,
Navapravat Academy for Management Education, Salipur, Cuttack

#### **PERSIONAL DETAILS**

Name	Mir Asadul Haque
Sex	Male
Date of Birth	15-05-1997
Languages	Hindi, English, Odiya

## **DECLARATION**

I do hereby declare that the above given statements are true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Mir Asadul Haque